so I'm recording this video because
there's something I want to talk about
and I don't feel like there's any other
person I conduct you about it who can
properly understand what to do except
for me so I'm talking to myself for a
moment um I wanted to get your advice
Joe as someone who's been through so
much um when you are trying to create
large scale social change trying to make
really big things happen and you find
yourself bumping up against the
inadequacies of other people's ability
to form relationships and follow through
and be dependable well what are you
depend on how do you find faith how do
you decide what's important to do well
I'll answer what I do is I go off into
myself I take walks I meditate I
contemplate oh right and all the things
that I'm doing all that I'm meditating
on or about how do I feel giving my time
to the people that I'm interacting with
do I feel like it's a relationship that
will nourish me or that will deplete me
something that gives or something that
takes something that helps or something
that hurts and I develop a very subtle
sensitivity about this because it's
helped me understand who I should work
with and hell and the other thing that I
do is I consider mission what am I
trying to achieve what's my purpose I'm
already entering into these
relationships because there's something
that's important for me and so I
presumably would still find it important
if I'm still here because I'm putting up
with being treated badly by someone else
in the relationship don't going well
and when I consider those two things how
do I feel about the relationship in the
experience and what is the right way to
be in relationship with myself through
those interactions because I have some
ability to influence how I behave I
don't necessarily have been plenty over
I other people behave and then the
second consideration is what am I doing
this for and how should I best go about
doing it I answer those questions and I
figure out how to move forward that
simple hope this helps